SHUYING YU

Goleta, CA, USA | +1 (510) 918-8012 | syu.shuying@gmail.com | github.com/esswhy | linkedin.com/in/shuyingyu/

Summary of Qualifications

Research: 7+ years in qualitative and quantitative analysis in human behavior and decision-making using statistics, hypothesis testing, exploratory data analysis, regression, visualizations, interpreting results, delivering presentations **Tools:** Microsoft Office, Google Workspace/G Suite, LaTeX, Qualtrics, GitHub, HTML/CSS, Tableau **Programming:** Advance in R; intermediate in Python; basic knowledge of Spark, SOL

Education

University of California, Santa Barbara (UCSB), CA

Sep 2018 – Jun 2023 (*Expected*)

Ph.D. Candidate, Psychological and Brain Sciences

M.A. Candidate, Statistics and Applied Probability w/ Data Science specialization

- 2018, 2019, Honorable Mention NSF Graduate Research Fellowship
- 2018, Eugene Cota-Robles Fellowship, 3-year award for merit and diversity

University of California, San Diego (UCSD), CA

Sep 2012 – Jun 2016

B.S., Cognitive Science, Honors w/ Highest Distinction

B.S., Psychology, Honors w/ Distinction

Relevant Projects from Courses

Machine Learning (course grade: A+), UCSB, CA

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

• Analyzed the 2016 U.S. presidential election dataset and census data in R including preprocessing, data wrangling, visualizations, classification and clustering methods (e.g., PCA, decision tree, logistic regression) to predict voting behavior; outcomes include delivering insights and interpreting results in a written report with collaborators

Big Data Analytics (course grade: A), UCSB, CA

Sep 2020 – Dec 2020

• Queried and evaluated big dataset of ~120k observations on hotel bookings in PySpark including preprocessing, exploratory data analysis, cross-validation, and applying methods (e.g., logistic regression, SVM, random forest) to statistical models to predict hotel demand, resulting in a written report and oral presentation along with collaborators

Relevant Experiences

Consumer Insights Graduate Intern, Jam City, CA

June 2021 - August 2021

- Collaborated internally and externally on 10 concurrent projects over 10 weeks by designing, programming, and analyzing surveys administered to thousands of consumers to interpret insights
- Created and delivered professional reports and presentations for weekly key stakeholder meetings to share and understand insights, receive and implement feedback, and discuss subsequent ideas for research which included adding new in-game features and investigating details of consumer churn, satisfaction, frustrations, and interests

Graduate Student Researcher & Analyst, UCSB, CA

Sep 2018 – Present

- Collaborate internally and externally on 3 large scale projects formulating research questions, selecting and applying methods, designing and analyzing survey data, and statistical analysis on human behavioral patterns (e.g., A/B testing, ANOVA, regression); outcomes include sharing data and providing weekly reports on results to key stakeholders
- Maintain reproducible workflow using .Rmd reports and version controlled projects with GitHub
- Create and deliver professional presentations at conferences and publish 2 peer-reviewed manuscripts related to human behavioral patterns and accessibility of science for women

Research Technician, UCSB, CA

Aug 2016 – Aug 2018

- Established own independent research project while running lab's larger study of recruiting 80+ subjects, budgeted finances worth \$800k+, moderating interviews, designing experiments, and creating and giving presentations
- Implemented user-centered design by partnering with experts to tailor experiments on improving user experience and testing for behaviors across 150+ subjects

Leadership

Diversity, Equity, & Inclusion Consultant & Organizer, UCSB, CA

Jun 2020 - Present

• Contribute to weekly meetings with stakeholders and create large scale policy changes with objectives and key results for implementation that highlight commitments to welcome and value diverse experiences

Beyond Academia Executive Organizer, UCSB, CA

Jun 2019 - Jun 2021

- Networked with stakeholders, communicated ideas across 15+ members, initiated new marketing strategies and sponsorships, and organized and lead meetings to build successful programs related to pursuing non-academic careers
- Managed 5-8 workshops and hosted 40+ industry professionals for 500+ registered attendees each year